BRETT WALBRUGH

LEAD TECHNICAL RECRUITER



CONTACT

- **©** 078 124 9040
- brettwalbrugh@gmail.com
- in www.linkedin.com/in/brett-walbrugh
- O Cape Town, South Africa

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Sound Engineering

SAE Institute - SA

Matriculated, 2015

Westerford High School

SKILLS

- Leadership
- Communication
- · Critical thinking
- Time management
- Motivation
- Charisma
- Resilience
- Discretion

INTERESTS

- Gardening
- Gym/Fitness
- Football
- Dogs
- Spontaneous Adventures

CANDIDATE PROFILE

An extroverted, witty and hardworking 26 year old with the aspiration and drive to achieve all my goals. From a young age, I entered into endeavours within the sales environment. Being a natural conversationalist this industry has helped me polish and finesse my existing personal attributes. My passion for people and agility in pressured circumstances have allowed me to gain great rapport with people very quickly, effortlessly and leaving lasting impressions. I am well received for my sense of humour, friendly nature and determined persona.

WORK EXPERIENCE

LEAD SENIOR IT RECRUITER (FULL TIME)

ACQUAINTED ACQUISITION | SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

I have dedicated my full attention to ensuring an overall streamlined talent acquisition experience for businesses trying to source highly skilled suitable candidates. Managing all the communication, talent recruitment and career placements to ensure maximum efficiency for the employee and the employer. Assisting companies both locally and globally in all facets of recruitment. My responsibilities specifically include: ongoing business development and nurturing business relationships, liaising with CEOs and HR personnel and searching for medium to high level IT positions. My skills include human resource management, marketing, hiring, business development, telecommunications, staffing services and technical recruitment. I play an integral role in ensuring candidates are best suited to the role, budget and company culture and fully immerse into the process to ensure attention to detail and accurate placements are always accomplished.

ROLES WORKED ON:

AZURE ARCHITECT | SIEBEL DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT | BUSINESS ANALYST | SQL DBA |
PERFORMANCE TEST SPECIALIST | AM DELIVERY MANAGER | SNR FRONTEND DEV | SENIOR ANGULAR
DEVELOPER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER | ANDROID/IOS DEV | LINUX ADMIN | KUBERNETES ADMIN.

INT. TALENT ACQUISITION (FULL TIME)

ZEUS TALENT | AUG 2021 - AUG 2022

I assist with world-class outsourced recruitment solutions. At Zeus, we aid in overcoming the challenges of finding the right fit for businesses in terms of culture, ambition, and talent. We add value to businesses and our team is experienced in all areas of recruitment. My key responsibilities include building strong, trustworthy relationships and accurate talent sourcing.

VOIP SALES SPECIALIST (FULL TIME)

BONLINE | MARCH 2021 - AUG 2021

I assisted in identifying business and technological needs for clients who had recently opened businesses. Good rapport, initiative and detailed product knowledge ensures a first call resolution for new entrepreneurs.

REAL ESTATE AGENT (PART TIME)

ENGEL & VÖLKERS | JUNE 2020 - FEB 2021

The selling and rental of properties in and around the Atlantic Seaboard.

CASINO SALES HOST (FULL TIME)

DIGIOUTSOURCE | JAN 2016 - JUNE 2020

Serving as an acquisitions and retentions agent, my role was to persuade new/existing clientele to use our online facilities and make their next deposit.